Guide to the National Council of Jewish Women, Pittsburgh Section Records, 1894-2011 AIS.1964.40
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- NCJW Oral History Projects, 1967-2001; XXVIII.
  - Oral History Course Curriculum Development, 1989-2007; 5.
    - "In Their Own Words" Oral History Interview Excerpts used for Course, 2001 (Box 115, Folder 52)
    - "In Their Own Words" Course Evaluations, 2001 (Box 115, Folder 53)
    - Pilot Class of Pittsburgh Jewish History based on Oral History Project Interviews Photographs, 2001 (Box 115, Folder 54)
    - "Funny, You Don't Look Jewish" Course Development, 2002 (Box 115, Folder 55)
    - Holocaust Course Development, 2003 (Box 115, Folder 56)
    - "Red, White, & Jew: Opportunities and Choices of Living in America" Course Materials, 2003-2004 (Box 115, Folder 57)
    - "Red, White & Jew" Course Development, 2004-2007 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - "In Their Own Words: Opportunities and Choices of Life in America" Course Materials, 2005 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - "In Their Own Words: Opportunities and Choices for Life in America" Power Point Slides, 2005 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - "In Their Own Words: Voices and Choices of Pittsburgh Jewry, 1850s- Today" Course Materials, 2007 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - "In Their Own Words..." Draft of Course Book, undated (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Oral History Interviews Compilation for Jewish History Courses, 1998-2008 (Box 117-119, Cassette 1-53)
    - Oral History Interviews Compilations used by Jill Aizenstein for Carnegie-Mellon University/ Osher Lifelong Learning Course on Jewish History, 2008 (Box 117-119, Cassette 54-56)
    - Oral History Interviews Compilations used by Jill Aizenstein for Carnegie-Mellon University/ Osher Lifelong Learning Course on Jewish History, 2008 (Box 120, Cassette 57-65)
  - Abstract and Index Project, 1981-2000; 6.
    The Abstract and Index Project was undertaken to in order to make to the recorded interviews searchable. The NCJW's goal was to create a polished, completed collection of interview abstracts and indices to complement their oral history interviews. The result of the abstract and index project was the creation of the guide to the collection, Pittsburgh and Beyond: The Experience of the Jewish Community. This subseries dates from 1981 to 2000 and is arranged chronologically.
    - Profile of Interview Respondent Categories, 1975-1982 (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - How to Index: Notes, 1982-1983 (Box 116, Folder 7)
    - Oral History Interviews Index Project Proposal to University of Pittsburgh, School of Information Science, 1984 (Box 116, Folder 8)
    - Oral History Index Project Materials, 1984-1989 (Box 116, Folder 9)
    - University of Pittsburgh School of Information Course "Oral History Collections: An Approach to their Approach", 1989 (Box 116, Folder 10)
    - Abstract and Index Project Funding, 1989-1992 (Box 116, Folder 11)
    - Inventory of Oral History Interview Tapes and Condition, 1989, undated (Box 116, Folder 12)
    - Abstract and Index Project PHMC and NEA Grant Applications and Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 116, Folder 13)
    - Application for Federal Assistance, 1990-1991 (Box 116, Folder 14)
    - Oral History Abstract and Index Directory Computer and Software Options, 1991 (Box 116, Folder 15)
    - Abstract and Index Project School of Information Science Internship, 1991 (Box 116, Folder 16)
    - Drafts of Subject Index with Editorial Mark-ups, 1991 (Box 116, Folder 17)
    - Overview and Evaluation Report of Software, 1992 (Box 116, Folder 18)
    - Abstracting and Indexing Forms, 1994 (Box 116, Folder 19)
    - Abstracting Guidelines, 1994-1995 (Box 116, Folder 20)
    - Meeting Notes with Carnegie-Mellon University regarding Abstract and Index Project, 1994-1995 (Box 116, Folder 21)
    - How to Abstract and Index, 1997 (Box 116, Folder 22)
    - Abstract Notes, 1997 (Box 116, Folder 23)
    - "Indexing and Abstracting for the NCJW Pittsburgh Section Oral History Project." Clipping from Bibliofile, December 3, 1997 (Box 116, Folder 24)
    - Status Reports from Betty Berger on writing Abstracts, 1998-2003 (Box 116, Folder 25)
    - Oral History Interviews Abstracts Addendums, 2006 (Box 116, Folder 26)
    - Interview Transcriptions of Leon Falk, Jr., Katharine Falk, and John Wolf, Sr., 2000 (Box 116, Folder 27)
    - Worksheet on Interview Abstract and Index Status, 2000 (Box 116, Folder 28)
    - Abstracting and Indexing Methodology and Use, 2001 (Box 116, Folder 29)
    - Pittsburgh and Beyond: The Experience of the Jewish Community Draft, 2002 (Box 116, Folder 30)
    - "Making an Index", undated (Box 116, Folder 31)
    - Spreadsheet of Interview Subjects, undated (Box 116, Folder 32)
  - Volunteer Interviewers Training Material, 1975-2000; 7.
    This subseries contains information on the NCJW, Pittsburgh Section created program for training volunteers to conduct oral history interviews. The material in this subseries dates from 1975 to 2000 and is arranged chronologically,
    - Training Sessions Participant Lists, May 1975- June 1976 (Box 116, Folder 33)
    - Training Session Notes, 1976 (Box 116, Folder 34)
    - Training Session Materials, 1981 (Box 116, Folder 35)
    - Volunteers Lists, 1981-1983 (Box 116, Folder 36)
    - Volunteer Interviewers Lists, 1984-2000 (Box 116, Folder 37)
    - Training Class Materials, December 1987 (Box 116, Folder 38)
    - Photographs of Volunteers, 1990s (Box 116, Folder 39)
    - Volunteer Evaluation Report, 1991 (Box 116, Folder 40)
    - Training Session Materials, 1993-2001 (Box 116, Folder 41)
    - Volunteer Training Packets, 2000 (Box 116, Folder 42)
    - Training Sessions Recordings for Oral History Project I, 1968 (Box 120, Cassette 66-73)
    - Training Sessions Recordings, 2000 (Box 120, Cassette 74-78)
  - Moving Images, 1980-1996; 7.
    This subseries contains two documentary films produced by NCJW based on the first two oral history projects.
    - "Bridges to History" 16mm color and sound print, 1980 (Box 120, Reel 1)
    - "Bridges to the Future" 16mm color and sound print, 1996 (Box 120, Reel 2)
    - National Council of Jewish Women's Oral History Website Project Launch, 2009
- Scrapbooks and Posters, 1960-1989; XXIX.
  This series contains large scrapbooks of newspaper clippings and NCJW brochures and leaflets documenting the clubs many activities. Also included are several posters and smaller printed images promoting NCJW's many educational programs, a list of members who contributed to the Friends of the Lounge group, and a framed certificate from Hebrew University thanking the members of NCJW for their efforts to promote education in Israel.
  - Scrapbook, 1960-1964 (Box 109, Oversize 1)
  - Friends of the Lounge Member List, 1950-1951 (Oversize 2)
  - Scrapbook, July 1970-May 1974 (Box 110, Oversize 3)
  - Scrapbook, June-April, 1974 (Oversize 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1986-1989 (Box 111, Oversize 1)
  - Posters and Matted Images Promoting NCJW Educational Programs, undated (Box 112, Oversize 1)
  - Certificate of Appreciation presented to NCJW by Hebrew University of Jerusalem for contributions to the John Dewey School of Education (Box 113, Oversize 1)
- Oversize material, XXX.
  This material was added to the finding aid in November 2010.
  - Picture of NCJW Day Care Center for the Elderly, 1983; 1. (Map-case 7, Drawer 1)
  - Chart depicting various Jewish groups and their scope, 2.